Guide to the Time Inc. TV-Cable Week Publishing and Business Records: Publisher Christopher Meigher Files 1981-1983, 1990 MS 3009-RG 49
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. TV-Cable Week Publishing and Business Records: Publisher Christopher Meigher Files
1981-1983, 1990
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 49
1 Linear feet in 1 record carton
This collection contains records from publisher Christopher Meigher regarding TV-Cable Week, a short-lived Time Inc. cable television listings magazine.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Historical Note
TV-Cable Week (TVCW) was a short-lived Time Inc. cable television listings magazine published from April to September of 1983. The idea began in 1979 when Time Inc. created the HBO Task Force to study the expansion of the HBO Program Guides. By 1982 after presentations to the Time Inc. Management Committee then to the Board of Directors, Time Inc. approved the launch and built offices for the magazine in White Plains, NY.
Christopher Meigher was named the publisher in July 1983 after publication began. He had recently served as Director of Corporate Circulation.
Provenance
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Related Materials
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains files from publisher Christopher Meigher regarding the cable television listings magazine TV-Cable Week (TVCW). Records include advertising and marketing plans, paste-ups of Cablemonth, presentations, reports comparing TVCW to its competitors, staff lists, Meigher's notes, budgets and financial analyses, and interoffice correspondence. Of interest are two memoranda; one transmits consumer reactions and the other includes a list of TVCW development milestones. This memorandum is in the Post Mortem file and looks to have been created in preparation to discuss why the magazine failed.
Arrangement
Meigher transferred one box of binders to the archives. His other TVCW files were housed with disparate executive files. The arrangement retains the original groupings with the general office files in the front in alphabetical order and the materials from the binders next in alphabetical order.
American periodicals -- History; Corporation records; Corporations -- History; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Organization files; Periodicals -- Publishing.; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Time, inc. -- Archives; Time, inc. -- History
- Key Background Information, 1983 (Offsite-box 4083, Folder 1-2)
- Post Mortem, 1983 (Offsite-box 4083, Folder 3-4)
- Task Force, 1981-1983 (Offsite-box 4083, Folder 5-6)
- Binders: Transfer Form, 1990 (Offsite-box 4083, Folder 7)
- Binders: Advertising Plan, 1983? (Offsite-box 4083, Folder 8)
- Binders: Cablemonth: "Sunburst" Approach 1-3, 1983? (Offsite-box 4083, Folder 9-11)
- Binders: Deal Book, 1982 November 9 (Offsite-box 4083, Folder 12)
- Binders: "Futures": Proposal for an Automated Database Publishing System, 1983 August 1 (Offsite-box 4083, Folder 13)
- Binders: Marketing Plan, 1983? (Offsite-box 4083, Folder 14)
- Binders: Presentation, 1983 June 27 (Offsite-box 4083, Folder 15)
- Binders: Publicity, 1983 (Offsite-box 4083, Folder 16)
- Binders: TV-Cable Week vs. Competition, 1983 February 1 (Offsite-box 4083, Folder 17)
- Binders: TV-Cable Week vs. Other Guides, 1983? (Offsite-box 4083, Folder 18)